# AMIT DIXIT

Senior Software Engineer



Hathras, PinCode- 204101 Uttar Pradesh (U.P.) India

+918745808601

☑ amit.amit1804@gmail.com

# SUMMARY

Experienced Java Developer with over 6+ years of experience in Software Industry. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction.

Experience in Object Oriented Programming ,Data Structure & Algorithms ,Design and problem solving skills

Proficient in using Design Patterns like Singleton, MVC, Factory, DAO, Builder, Observer etc. Extensive programming experience in developing web based applications using Java 7/8, spring 4, Spring Boot, Akka etc.

High level understating on Amazon Web Service (AWS) native services EC2, S3, VPC, RDS, Dynamo DB, etc. Experienced in working in Agile Methodology using JIRA , Rally . Good experience in version management tools using GitLab, Github, Bitbucket, Crucible, and build tools like Bamboo, Jenkins.

# INTERESTS/HO BBIES

- Cricket
- Badminton
- Problem Solving
- Researching

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Jan 2022 -

Senior Software Engineer

May 2022

Infosys

- Collaborated with project managers to select ambitious, but realistic coding milestones on pre-release software project development.
- Updated old code bases to modern development standards, improving
- Developed clear specifications for project plans using customer requirements.
- · Discussed issues with team members to provide resolution and apply best
- Translated customer requirements into written use cases.
- Introduced agile methodologies and development best practices to division to enhance product development.
- Coordinated with project management on database development timelines.

Jan 2021 -Dec 2021

Software Engineer

IHS Markit (S&P Global)

- · Worked with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- · Reviewed project specifications and designed technology solutions that met or exceeded performance expectations.
- · Provided guidance and mentored less-experienced staff members.
- Developed robust, scalable, modular and API-centric infrastructures.
- Developed clear specifications for project plans using customer requirements.
- Delivered unit-tested systems within customer-prescribed timeframes.

Jun 2019 -Oct 2020

Software Associate Platform Level I

Publicis Sapient

- · Offered friendly and efficient service to Verizon Customer, handled challenging situations with ease.
- Developed robust, scalable, modular and API-centric infrastructures.
- Collaborated with clients to define solution requirements.
- Developed clear specifications for project plans using customer requirements.
- Designed enhancements and updates for subsystems of end-user applications software running on local, networked and Internet-based platforms.
- Participated in architecture, design and implementation of back-end features using Java, Play, Akka.
- Promoted experience with Kubernetes, Docker and Amazon Web Services.

Nov 2015 -Mar 2019

Associate Consultant II

AToS Syntel

- Designed enhancements and updates for subsystems of end-user applications software running on local, networked and Internet-based platforms.
- Analyzed proposed technical solutions based on customer requirements.
- Coordinated efficient large-scale software deployments.
- Promoted experience with Kubernetes, Docker and Amazon Web Services.
- Offered experience with Java ,Spring,Hibernate,SpringBoot and AWS.

# EDUCATION

2012 - 2015

Master of Computer Applications

Institute of Management Studies

### SKILLS



Core Java

Spring Framework Spring IOC, JDBC emplate etc



Spring Boot

Micro-service implementation

Play Micro-service implementation



Spring Batch/ Streams Batch Processing

Hibernate



React

Javascript Framework

Apache Tomcat

Web Server

ORM Framework



JBoss Server

Application Server



Sybase DB / Oracle DB Relational Database



AWS

Amazon Web Service



Intelij Idea / Eclipse



Eclipse

## CERTIFICATIONS

Jun-17 -

Oracle Certified Associate Java Prograame - 8

till date OCAJP-8